Jose Gomez, Front End Developer

832-613-3881, gomez.jose853@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am an experienced developer with over 10 years of development experience. I have strong knowledge of JavaScript libraries such as React, Node and JavaScript ES6. My experience includes collaborating with UI/UX designers creating brand guidelines for clients and implementing them for a consistent experience for the user and the owner. Excellent time managing skills, and communication skills with the ability to manage multiple projects to meet deadlines.

REACT PROJECTS

ArchStudio

NextJS app deployed on Vercel. Technologies used: React, Contentful HeadLess

Demo URL: https://archstudio-react.vercel.app/

Fine Watch Bank

Basic shopping cart functionality with React, React Context, React Router, React Hooks, and uploaded to Netlify.

Demo URL: https://trusting-archimedes-c373a0.netlify.app/

Netflix Clone

A Netflix clone project with RESTful API integrations from TMBD and YouTube built with React, React Router, React Hooks, Netlify.

Demo URL: https://romantic-khorana-083a59.netlify.app/

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

May 2021

Front End Developer, Cart.com

Houston

- Collaborating and contributing with UI/UX designers in developing starter theme for storefront platform
 to create components that can be reusable throughout the theme.
- Building the starter theme with ES6 JavaScript, CSS and HTML and establishing version control with GitHub.
- Providing technical leadership while taking ownership of starter theme and developing documentation for developers on feature releases.
- Meeting with product managers and account leads to understand the needs of clients and improving the
 positive impact of users' experience.

Apr 2016 — May 2021

Front End Developer, Forthea Interactive

Houston

- Built prototype forms suitable for API testing with WordPress to test custom integration with CRM's such as Salesforce, HubSpot, and Zoho.
- Designed web layouts with good design principles and user interaction standards with visual aesthetic components such as: layout, fonts, color, animations, graphic elements
- Maintained client sites in WPEngine, communicated potential site updates and provided support when
 updates affected client sites.
- Optimized landing pages based of Hotjar and Google Analytics data to generate conversion.

May 2012 — Apr 2016

Web Developer, MMI Agency

Houston

- Designed and developed custom mobile friendly WordPress sites.
- Worked with account leads to establish client expectations and deadlines.
- Collaborated with designers creating brand standards for web.

SKILLS

React jQuery
SQL CSS
JavaScript PHP
ES6 NPM

EDUCATION

Jul 2009 — Jun 2012

Bachelors of Fine Arts, The Art Institutes

Houston